Guide to the Richard H. Fogel Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Richard H. Fogel papers
1912-1974
1968-1974
SC0882
Fogel, Richard H.
4.75 Linear feet
A significant portion of this collection includes agendas, clippings, case files, reports, and resolutions related to the national and California Sigma Delta Chi Freedom of Information Committees. Founded in 1961, the Sigma Delta Chi Foundation promotes excellence and ethics in journalism. The Freedom of Information Committee monitors press freedoms across the nation, and is often called upon to intervene in instances where the media is restricted. Included are several case files from high profile courtroom cases in California and throughout the nation dating from the late 1960s and early 1970s, as well as records related to the committee's support of journalists who were expelled from the United Nations in 1971. Also included are clippings, correspondence, case files from several California university newspapers pertaining to freedom of the press issues, and the syllabus and class notes from History of Western Civilization, 1946. The collection also includes a 1912 scrapbook belonging to Fogel's father, Moe M. Fogel, which contains clippings from several Los Angeles area newspapers.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Richard H. Fogel earned his AB in Journalism from Stanford University in 1947. Fogel served as the chairman of the Sigma Delta Chi California Freedom of Information Committee in 1969 and as the national Freedom of Information Committee chairman in 1972. During this time Fogel worked as the assistant managing editor of the Oakland Tribune.
Description of the Collection
A significant portion of this collection includes agendas, clippings, case files, reports, and resolutions related to the national and California Sigma Delta Chi Freedom of Information Committees. Founded in 1961, the Sigma Delta Chi Foundation promotes excellence and ethics in journalism. The Freedom of Information Committee monitors press freedoms across the nation, and is often called upon to intervene in instances where the media is restricted. Included are several case files from high profile courtroom cases in California and throughout the nation dating from the late 1960s and early 1970s, as well as records related to the committee's support of journalists who were expelled from the United Nations in 1971. Also included are clippings, correspondence, case files from several California university newspapers pertaining to freedom of the press issues, and the syllabus and class notes from History of Western Civilization, 1946. The collection also includes a 1912 scrapbook belonging to Fogel's father, Moe M. Fogel, which contains clippings from several Los Angeles area newspapers.
Access Terms
Fogel, Richard H.; Society of Professional Journalists (U.S.); Society of Professional Journalists, Sigma Delta Chi.; Freedom of information--United States.; Freedom of the press--United States--20th century.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accesion ARCH-2007-278
  - National FOI-Sigma Delta Chi-Spangler (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - National FOI-SDX Common Cause (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - National FOI-SDX Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - National FOI-SDX Courier News vs. Police, Elgin, IL (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - National FOI-SDX Chronology File #2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National FOI-SDX Chronology File #3 (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - National FOI-SDX Chronology File #3 (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - National FOI-SDX Chronology File #3 (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - National FOI-SDX Anderson Papers (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - National FOI-SDX Annual Report File No. 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - National FOI-SDX Annual Report File No. 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - National FOI-SDX Brooks Darlington Background Briefing (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - National FOI-SDX Ervin Committee 1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - National FOI-SDX Center for Study of Responsive Law (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - National FOI-SDX Court Report General (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - National FOI-SDX Committee Members (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - FOI-Gen. Public Records Bill (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - FOI-Gen. Reagan Administration (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - FOI-General Report (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - FOI-Gen. Resolutions (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - FOI-Gen. Rule 980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - FOI-Gen. Supervisors Secrecy FOI (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - FOI-Computers (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - FOI-Gen.Theta Sigma Phi (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - FOI-Gen. Underground Press (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - FOI-Gen. Campus Editors-College Papers (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - FOI-Gen. Campus Editors-College Papers (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - FOI-Gen. Campus Editors-Student Press Guidelines (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - FOI-Gen. Tarquino (Cal. Prof.) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - FOI-Gen. Campus Editors-Karin Holzmeister (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - FOI-Gen. Campus Editors-San Francisco State (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - FOI-Gen. Campus Editors-San Francisco State (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - FOI-Gen. Campus Editors-Spangler Study (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - FOI-Gen. Campus Editors-Spangler Study/S.F. State (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - FOI-Gen. Objectivity (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - FOI-Gen. Confidential (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - FOI-Gen. Contempt (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - FOI-Gen. Correspondence, Gen. File #1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Open Meeting (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - FOI-Gen. International (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - FOI-Gen. Successor (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - FOI-Gen. ACLU (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - FOI-Gen. Annual Reports (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - FOI-Gen. Broadcasting-General (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - FOI-Gen. Broadcasting-Subpoena (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - FOI-Gen. Broadcasting-Nixon/Agnew (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - FOI-Gen. Broadcasting-Advertising (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - FOI-Gen. Broadcasting-Bylaws (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - FOI-Gen. Bulletin (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bridge, Peter-New Jersey-Ads and Pledge Sheets (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Bridge, Peter-New Jersey-Acknowledgements (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Bridge, Peter-New Jersey-Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Bridge, Peter-New Jersey-Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Bridge, Peter-New Jersey-Memos to the File (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Bridge, Peter-New Jersey-News Clippings (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Sigma Delta Chi (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Black Panthers (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Paul M. Branzburg-Kentucky (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Sheppard vs. Maxwell Case (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Mills College (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Ted Kennedy (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Merced Sun-Star Case (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Corona Case (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Morning Papers-File No. 1 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Chicago Clothing Workers vs. Chicago Tribune (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Angela Davis (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Budville Case (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - The Rights of Newsmen to Protect Their Sources of Information under California Law, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Legal Documents (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Newspaper Articles & Dispatches (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Personal-California FOI (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - National FOI-Sigma Delta Chi-UN News Access Committee (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - National FOI-Sigma Delta Chi-White House Rules & Regulations (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - National FOI-Sigma Delta Chi-UN News Access Committee-Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - National FOI-Sigma Delta Chi-White House Releases & News Stories (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - National FOI-Sigma Delta Chi-UN News Access Committee-Opinion of Counsel (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - National FOI-Sigma Delta Chi-UN News Access Committee-Editor/Comments (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Report of the California FOI Committee Part II (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Ventura (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Clippings (Including APNEC) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - National FOI-Sigma Delta Chi-UN News Access Resolution (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - SDX: A Report on the Use of a Search Warrant Against the Stanford Daily-By Fogel, 1971 May 8 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - National FOI-Sigma Delta Chi-UN News Access-Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Harrison Gray Otis/Judge Fitzgerald Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Pacific Telephone Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - National FOI-Sigma Delta Chi-UN News Access-Miscellaneous (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - National FOI-Sigma Delta Chi-UN News Access-Miscellaneous (2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Scrapbook (Moe M. Fogel) (Box 8)
  - Syllabus from History of Western Civilization and class notes, 1946 (Box 9)